<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shravan Asati</title><link>https://shravanasati.me/</link><description>Recent content on Shravan Asati</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 17:52:02 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shravanasati.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding and breaking the Caesar cipher</title><link>https://shravanasati.me/posts/caesar-cipher/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 17:52:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shravanasati.me/posts/caesar-cipher/</guid><description>The caesar cipher is one the oldest known ciphers known to mankind. As the story goes, the Roman emperor Julius Caesar used it extensively for military communications. It is a simple substitution cipher and is not fit for any modern usage, since it is a trivial task to break it. However, it may be worthwhile to learn the roots of cryptography, as this cipher leads to more advanced ones like the Vigènere cipher and the unbreakable one-time pad cipher.</description></item><item><title>How Everything Suddenly Goes Berserk in Production</title><link>https://shravanasati.me/posts/production-berserk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 18:00:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shravanasati.me/posts/production-berserk/</guid><description>I often tend to take a look at the websites I&amp;rsquo;ve deployed - to check whether they are still online or not (I should use cutting edge tools like kubernetes). It also helps with the gloom that appears on my face when I view the website analytics.
One such time was the fine summer morning of 13th June 2024. I woke up late and checked my mobile for notifications (there weren&amp;rsquo;t any).</description></item><item><title>Achieving Infinite WPM in MonkeyType using Python</title><link>https://shravanasati.me/posts/selenium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2024 00:32:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://shravanasati.me/posts/selenium/</guid><description>So I have this one friend who constantly boasts about his sub-200 WPM typing speed. I tried competing with him but couldn&amp;rsquo;t manage it above 100 WPM. I decided it was not worth the effort since I could beat him with the help of Python! :)
We&amp;rsquo;ll be using the awesome selenium library for this task.
Prerequisites Just intermediate-level knowledge of Python and HTML tags. That&amp;rsquo;s all. I&amp;rsquo;ll be explaining selenium along the way.</description></item></channel></rss>